Contact

new Delhi absingh3010@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/abhinxx (LinkedIn) follege.com (Company) abhinavsingh.carrd.co/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Start-ups Product Design Strategy

Publications

Application of Artificial Intelligence in placement sector: A futuristic approach

Abhinav Singh

Founder and CEO at Follege || I Build Stuff New Delhi

Summary

Abhinav believes in lean startup, transparency and hustle.

He Co-Founded his first venture in the 1rst year of his college and Clocked more than #90,000 revenue in its first 2 month only!!

Currently Abhinav is working on @Follege which is his 2nd venture, with his team consisting of industry experts from companies like: Wallmart, Microsoft, Goldman Sachs, Airtel, Jupiter and many more, to change the Indian College's Edutech landscape.

Expertise and Interests:

Startups || Product Management || UI/UX Design || Product Design and Thinking || Marketing || Strategy || Business Analysis || Copy Writing || Web Development

Before dropping a connection request, please also add your reason, anything will work- like interested in joining team, ask me about my venture, or just anything casual!

What exactly is Follege? Read below

Experience

Follege
Founder & CEO
November 2019 - Present (10 months)
New Delhi Area, India

We all know that college is the time for networking and exploration, but despite that, the harsh reality is like we don't even know about our own classmates, let alone the other college students.

Also, in a country like India where the education infrastructure is not strong, there is a huge gap between students and administration.

And these big social platforms like FB-Instagram, they are nothing but a sea of information, due to which 60-70% of important information is often missed out!

And the list of problems goes on!

Hence,

Colleges as an environment need a better platform and we at follege aims to become a sense of belongingness for every student!

Wrapping up Follege is:

For college students who want to leverage college life to its full potential, follege is a student only social platform that connects college students across the globe; unlike Facebook, Instagram or Whatsapp, it provides students access to personalised content, career opportunities, and an official platform to stay connected with college administration and alumni.

Entrepreneurship Cell, DTU(Formerly DCE)

1 year 11 months

Strategic Partnerships Department
July 2019 - June 2020 (1 year)

Co Head November 2018 - July 2019 (9 months)

Society Member August 2018 - November 2018 (4 months) New Delhi Area, India

http://www.ecelldtu.in/

Entrepreneurship Cell, DTU aims to bring together the entrepreneurial passions to converge on a common platform.

Since its nascence in 2008, E-Cell DTU has aimed to bring to the forth the entrepreneur dwelling within so many of us. To accomplish the goal of serving as an efficacious platform for networking and interaction, E-Cell DTU has been organising a host of events. As the legacy goes on, the E Cell brings to you a series of events and hopes to receive a delectable response.

Rise Delhi

6 months

Co-Founder

August 2019 - December 2019 (5 months)

New Delhi, Delhi

Earlier I co-founded the startup Rise Delhi (http://risedelhi.com), We generate around Rs.90,000 in our first 1.5 months. Although I quit it because of different end goals with the road ahead.

Product and Marketing Manager

July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months)

New Delhi, Delhi, India

Handled the product development and marketing vertical of the venture

Defence Research and Development Organisation (DRDO)

Artificial Intelligence Intern

June 2019 - August 2019 (3 months)

New Delhi, Delhi, India

trainee at DESIDOC, DRDO researching on applications of machine learning and artificial intelligence.

Developed a chatbot for the DRDO using NLP and Dialogflow. I got recognition for the most applicable chatbot. My supervisor was planning to deploy it on the Facebook page of DRDO but we couldn't get the permission.

Brightigo™

Associate Product Manager

May 2019 - July 2019 (3 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Worked under the supervision of Product managers of Airtel, Jio, Cointribe, Spinny, Flipkart.

- Learned As and Bs of product management directly from the Industry Experts

- Customer Acquisition served as the primary goal for Brightigo, worked on the marketing and product strategy and roadmap for user acquisition
- Ideated and tested new online funnel marketing for Enrolling module and increased the total bookings by 30%.
- Lead the tech and marketing team of the Brightigo
- -Organised a Product Meetup where more than 60 product leaders and enthusiasts took part

D_CODER

User Experience Designer October 2018 - June 2019 (9 months)

New Delhi Area, India

D_CODER is a Delhi based technical team who won many Hackathons including The Smart India Hackathon 2018, Vistara Hackathon 2017, Hack with Zafin tech, Technovate 2018, DCB bank Hackathon, etc.

Awign

Sales Business Development April 2019 - May 2019 (2 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Worked with the team of IIT Alumni on a PAN India level, executing the ground business development and market research, with its Omni-present, Cost-effective and Reliable Student Workforce.

Dell

5 months

Marketing Intern
January 2019 - March 2019 (3 months)

New Delhi, Delhi

Worked on the Dell Futurist Program. Got promoted and selected as the top 50

Main role and responsibilities:

- the layout of the Marketing roadmap.
- Progress monitoring and research
- Working with the lead Dell team to plan operations
- Closely operating and collaborating with Product managers of Dell

Campus Ambassador

November 2018 - January 2019 (3 months)

New Delhi Area, India

I was the Dell Student Partner

Young Engine™

6 months

Project Manager

January 2019 - February 2019 (2 months)

Lead several major projects leading the team of 40 individuals

Marketing And Business Associate

November 2018 - January 2019 (3 months)

New Delhi, Delhi

I was heading the marketing and partnership department of the Young Engine

Community Manager

September 2018 - November 2018 (3 months)

New Delhi Area, India

YE is a large community of enablers, globally-minded young leaders.

Many companies have tried to gain access to the students of various colleges but have failed miserably.

We position ourselves as a solution to this problem, filling this massive void between students and companies. Now companies can devote more time and focus on enhancing the quality of their product, leaving the effective marketing part to be driven by us for them.

Forget the hassle of communicating with various college unions and administration, and enjoy the benefits of having one point of contact for everything.

Concurrently, our dual focus is to simplify and qualitatively improve the college experience of students.

We as a community not only enables students to get guaranteed opportunities but also focus on building the skill set which one can leverage later in his professional life and all of this requires their contribution to the mission we are heading with. Young Engine aims to bridge the gap between renowned companies looking for trained undergraduates and those enthusiastic individuals who are ready to grow as a professional by working with them. Thereby, we offer students to work on live projects of different brands.

To put this into reality, a team of some incredibly talented people, who have worked with companies like Uber, Zee, BCG, PwC, Facebook, Google, Amazon, etc., coordinated together to expand their wonderful skills and ideas.

We have already built some resourceful network with 50+ companies like Investopad, One Cowork, Almora Blockspace, Stirring Minds and their number keeps increasing.

Internshala

Internshala Student Partner (ISP) 14 September 2018 - October 2018 (2 months)

New Delhi Area, India

Lead the Campus Ambassador Program for Internshala. Honestly, I do not suggest opting for this!

Education

Delhi College of Engineering

BTech - Bachelor of Technology, Computer Software

Engineering · (2018 - 2022)

Delhi Technological University (Formerly DCE)
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Software
Engineering · (2018 - 2022)